Komang A.

Web, Mobile & DevOps Engineer

komang@chazzuka.com

Summary

An experienced software architect from Bali, Indonesia with strong knowledge in web programming, mobile application development, database, server and project management. Had been involved in various web programming & mobile application development projects, from simple static website to scalable multi-tier b2b/b2c web application with millions of users and high concurrency in multi-tenant data center architecture. Particularly interested in scalable client-server application with big base data and using various technology at it best to support it. Lately more into devops related and mobile technology.

Experience

CTO at MatahariMall.com

May 2015 - Present (6 months)

building the fastest growing e-commerce in Indonesia.

Technical Advisor at Kosong Satu Network

December 2013 - March 2015 (1 year 4 months)

An ambitious business development company which has several business units in various category includes: hospitality, construction, digital media. Responsibility is to oversee the whole technical operation of the company, business units and some dedicated partners, supervise product development lifecycle in technical aspects, lead the whole IT team to continuously increment quality of deliverables, analyse and translate business requirements into technical guidelines

Partner at Fogitive Media Kreasi

October 2011 - December 2014 (3 years 3 months)

Business/Team Management and Product Development

Technical Lead at OLX Indonesia

February 2009 - March 2013 (4 years 2 months)

The biggest classified site in Indonesia, part of global Naspers portfolio Responsibility is to oversee the whole product development lifecycle in technical aspects, lead IT team to continuously increment quality of deliverables, actively research about technology, techniques, best practices to increment quality of product and development process.

Technical Lead at Bali IT Solusi

December 2006 - December 2008 (2 years 1 month)

An outsourcing company based in Bali, Indonesia provides dedicated designers/programmers to work closely with various overseas clients to develop custom solution for their business needs. Responsibility is to oversee the whole technical procedures and process between clients and company, translate business requirements into technical guidelines, technology decision and team management.

CMS & E-Commerce Developer at Soltria Europe BV

August 2003 - December 2006 (3 years 5 months)

A software house focused on developing CMS/e-commerce web applications for European market using microsoft technology. Responsibility is to develop custom built CMS/e-commerce engine using ASP 3.0 and MySQL, deploy and customize as needed to match client's business processes. porting raw design into full HTML template

Languages

English

Bahasa Indonesia

(Professional working proficiency)

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

jQuery

MySQL

PHP

Apache

CSS

Nginx

JavaScript

Mobile Applications

Web Applications

E-commerce

Python

ActionScript

Ruby on Rails

C#

Web Development

MongoDB

Zend Framework

HTML 5

Front-end

Node.js

Java

Web Design

Software Development

Redis

Solr

ASP.NET

Android

AJAX

Git

HTML5

Laravel

ElasticSearch

Go

AngularJS

Project Management

Team Management

PostgreSQL

Education

STIKOM Bali

Information Systems and Technology, 2013 - 2015

LP3I Bali

Information Technology, 2000 - 2003

Interests

Design, Programming, Digital Arts, Entrepreneurships, Travelling

Komang A.

Web, Mobile & DevOps Engineer

komang@chazzuka.com



10 people have recommended Komang

"Most of you guys will know him as Komang or as Ariel. I know him as one of the best technical guy you can aspire to be. We have shared countless hours of talks over beer, about the fundamentals of this incredible passion we both have about technology. He is one of the Top 1% of techies who really knows what he is talking about inspired by actual hands on practical experience. Dozens of languages, ideals of different design patters and most importantly the wisdom to choose which is best for a specific task. His experience in micro and macro code management (and writing) is an inspiration for me. A guys who is humble by nature, superb guitarist/musician and a role model for any tech practitioner. Just have a chat with him and get inspired!"

— Batista Harahap, was with another company when working with Komang at Fogitive Media Kreasi

"First of all, he is one of the brightest people I know -- from speed-of-thought perspective. Natural genius bastard who really proud of himself. Despite the fact that he is imperfect, he is a very good team leader. I learned many things from him and his code. He is not like anyone who kept knowledge for themself. A highly recommended person."

— **Leonardo Situmorang**, reported to Komang at OLX Indonesia

"Ariel is the MVP (Most Valuable Player) in IT field, simply explained. Strong, wide and deep understanding of IT problem and a lot of back-end system experience are his built-in ability to found a great solution. Furthermore he is a super-casual fun and crazy partner at the same time. No doubt, I recommended him to be part of your team then find out yourself."

— Cecep Mirasz Albari, worked directly with Komang at OLX Indonesia

""A rockstar team needs a rockstar geeks and this is where Komang comes in. I find it really rewarding to work with someone who has a lot of experience about IT, drive your determination to the fullest and beat the deadlines while delivering topmost quality. dedicated, a hard worker and proactive professional. He is definitely a valuable asset to the team and a great personality to work with, Keep Rockin Dude"

— Irfan Badruzaman, worked with Komang at OLX Indonesia

"Komang Arthayasa is a professional and responsible man, hard worker, a man with multi talent, willing to share knowledge, and quickly in addressing problems in the work (great solver / a skillful person with many brilliant ideas on his mind). Always give priority to work smarter, so that time is used very efficiently, very great coder, and he is great as a friend too... Nice to have a colleague like Komang Arthayasa... All thumbs up for Komang Arthayasa, and I recommend him..."

— Hendry Mokoginta, worked directly with Komang at OLX Indonesia

"I have know Komang (which most people usually called him Ariel) and working with him for more than one year. He is a very passionate person in IT world. When talking about skills, there's no doubt about it, I guarantee 100%. He has a good sense of humor, also a humble person, I bet you wouldn't thought he were a Head Developer if you met him directly. He's an idealist person. When it comes to work and responsibility, I give him two thumbs up, because he will ensure the work/task/project that entrusted to him -- bring a great result in the given time. He has a capability to lead a team, bring the team to work together, and delegate task according to the best ability of each person in his team. Therefore I highly recommend him."

- Steven Pangemanan, reported to Komang at OLX Indonesia

"Working with Komang Arthayasa I found him as a person with great experience and deep expertise of IT solutions. Komang Arthayasa was one of the most dedicated professionals through his work at Tokobagus. Careful co-worker. Detail oriented strategist. Knowledge of IT technologies in connection with modern way of managing make Komang an employee with really huge potential."

— Gunawan Sanjaya, worked with Komang at OLX Indonesia

"Person who can you rely on when some task need to be done immediately."

— Anwar Hartando, worked with Komang at OLX Indonesia

"As I remember, Komang (Ariel) Arthayasa was a very productive person. Ariel did an exceptional job on the recent project. He is a dedicated, reliable and strong software engineer, with good sense of humor. Proactive and deadline oriented. Very good people manager. With Ariel, every problem had a solution. Can focus on many tasks at once. Glad to have him on our team !! Keep Rockin Dude !!!"

— Albert Huwae, worked indirectly for Komang at OLX Indonesia

"First off, he was senior to me at Indowebservices. In my opinion Komang is a self-confidence, multi-talented web developer. He is good at ASP programming, and also has a very high attention to details while onto design."

— Azwar Rosyadi, worked indirectly for Komang at Soltria Europe BV

Contact Komang on LinkedIn